Guide to the Katharine Brownell Collier Papers, 1895-1977 (bulk 1904-1934)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES VI. PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Katharine Brownell Collier, Family, and Friends
    - Photographs, Miscellaneous (Folder 3.115)
    - Dr. Peter Collier, elder brother of John A. Collier, portrait, ca. 1920s; (1 item) (Folder 4.37)
    - Billy Wheeler, son of Loraine Wheeler, cousin of KBC, snapshots, 1931; (2 items) (Folder 4.38)
    - see also folder 2.45
    - Jameson Collier Brownell snapshots, 1973; (2 items) (Folder 4.39)
    - Bay Shore High School teachers and principal, snapshots, ca. 1908-1911; (2 items) (Folder 4.40)
    - Bell, Cora N. with Jessica Kennedy Pullis, snapshots, ca. 1908-1911; (2 items) (Folder 4.41)
    - King, Annie G., VC 1909 head and shoulders portrait, photographer: Gustave Lorey, (1 item) (Folder 4.42)
    - Lunt, Raymond L. full length portrait, photographer: Finley, Chicago, ca. 1906-1910; (1 item) (Folder 4.43)
    - MacMahon, Ada "Latin VI,", 1906-1907; (1 item) (Folder 4.44)
    - Martin, Marjorie, senior portrait, Packer photographer: Butler, NY, 1906; (1 item) (Folder 4.45)
    - Rhame, Eleanora "May" Davis, full length portrait, photographer: Scherer, NY, ca. 1909; (1 item) (Folder 4.46)
    - Rhame, William sitting on steps of building, ca. 1931; (1 item) (Folder 4.47)
    - see also folder 6.39
    - West, Ethel, full length portrait, photographer: Butler, NY, 1900; (1 item) (Folder 4.48)
    - Two unidentified women, snapshot, n.d.; (1 item) (Folder 4.49)
  - Trips taken by Katharine Brownell Collier
    - Snapshots of a trip to Mt. Mansfield, VT: lake, mountain, lodge, 2 unidentified women "friends of Mabel [Stone (?)],", ca. 1910s; (4 items) (Folder 4.50)
    - Snapshots of a trip to Maine Sebago Lake, Portland, Kennebunkport, ca. 1920s; (9 items) (Folder 4.51)
    - Snapshots of a trip to Wiscasset, Maine: Bemis-Hobson house, 1930; (2 items) (Folder 4.52)
    - Trip to Florida taken by KBC and Laura Brownell Collier "Uncle Ervin's winter home,", ca. 1930s; (4 items) (Folder 4.53)
    - Trip to Mediterranean region Rome, Italy: ruins, tour group at final dinner, etc., 1967; (5 items) (Folder 4.54)
    - Trip to Mediterranean region Jerusalem, Gethsemane, Jordan, etc., 1967; (8 items) (Folder 4.55)
    - Miscellaneous trips (Folder 6.39)
  - Landscapes
    - Bay Shore High School, NY exterior view, ca. 1908-1911; (1 item) (Folder 4.56)
    - Bay Shore, NY: "the cliff," harbor, wooded area, ca. 1908-1911; (6 items) (Folder 4.57)
    - "Camel's Hump showing 'couching [sic] lion' shape" photographer: T.S. Dean, 28 August 1925; (1 item) (Folder 4.58)
    - Lake Champlain, snapshot, n.d.; (1 item) (Folder 4.59)
    - Middlebury (?) VT: "outer creek,", n.d.; (1 item) (Folder 4.60)
    - Vassar College: Main Building, Sunset Lake, Ely Hall, photographer: Wolven mounted on Saltford Florist ad, ca. 1904-1908; (3 items) (Folder 4.61)
- SERIES VII. ADVERTISEMENTS SENT TO KATHARINE BROWNELL COLLIER
  - Connecticut: New London, The Brainerd and Armstrong Co., 1908; (5 items) (Folder 5.100)
  - Illinois: Chicago, The Albert Teachers Agency, 1908; (4 items) (Folder 5.101)
  - Massachusetts: Boston and Holyoke, Emerson Shoes, American Stenophile School, White and Wyckoff Mfg. Co., 1905-1908; (5 items) (Folder 5.102)
  - Michigan: Detroit, Pathfinders of America, ca. 1930; (3 items) (Folder 5.103)
  - New Jersey: East Orange, Anna Elizabeth Wade, Specialist in Fund-raising Plans, (5 items) (Folder 5.104)
  - New York: Adirondack region, Lake Placid Club, resorts, camps, 1934, n.d.; (4 items) (Folder 5.105)
  - New York: Albany, Albany Teachers' Agency, Gustave Lorey, photographer includes application partially completed by KBC, 1907-1908; (9 items) (Folder 5.106)
  - New York: Bay Shore ladies' tailor, ca. 1908-1911; (1 item) (Folder 5.107)
  - New York: Brooklyn, "morning musicales," Frederick Loeser and Co., waitress/maid, Standard Tour and Travel Bureau, 1907-1929; (8 items) (Folder 5.108)
  - New York: Brooklyn, apt. building, dentist, Lincoln Savings Bank of Brooklyn, Botanical Garden, 1930-1934; (9 items) (Folder 5.109)
  - New York: Brooklyn, National City Bank, Edison Electric Co., Brooklyn Engineering Inst., Martin's Department Store, n.d.; (4 items) (Folder 5.110)
  - New York: Brooklyn, advertisement, n.d.; (1 item, oversized) (Folder 9.6)
  - New York: Manhattan, Pond's Extract, Colgate, Oliver typewriter, dressmaker, Kellogg's Teachers' Agency, Fisk Teachers' Agency, The Tribune, scientific astrologer, 1896-1909; (14 items) (Folder 5.111)
  - New York: Manhattan, Life Extension Inst., Malkin Conservatory of Music, Girls Vacation Fund, 1919-1945; (10 items) (Folder 5.112)
  - New York: Manhattan, antique dealer, glassworker, interior decorator, n.d.; (12 items) (Folder 5.113)
  - New York: Poughkeepsie, Consolidated Dry Goods, Luckey Platt, Saltford Florist, 1904-1906; (9 items) (Folder 5.114)
  - New York: Poughkeepsie, tailors, dressmakers, sporting goods, 1907; (12 items) (Folder 5.115)
  - New York: Poughkeepsie, dentist, Luckey Platt, Collingwood Opera House, 1908; (14 items) (Folder 5.116)
  - New York: Poughkeepsie, Luckey Platt, Collingwood Opera House, Peter Adriance and Sons, ca. 1904-1908; (8 items) (Folder 5.117)
  - Pennsylvania: Philadelphia, Penn Publishing Co., n.d.; (1 item) (Folder 5.118)
  - South Carolina: Charleston, Chamber of Commerce, n.d.; (1 item) (Folder 5.119)
  - Vermont: Burlington and Williston Green Mountain Camp, VT Association for the Crippled, 1931-1969, n.d.; ( 8 items) (Folder 5.120)
  - Washington, D.C. Hills Publishing Co., National Resources Planning Board, 1907-1941, n.d.; (9 items) (Folder 5.121)
  - Wyoming: Cheyenne, The Handicraft, 1907; (2 items) (Folder 5.122)
  - Advertisements sent to KBC, Miscellaneous (Folder 6.40)
- SERIES VIII. POSTCARDS
  - Postcards of Europe
    - Olympia Museum, Athens; French soldiers; The Cathedral, Berlin, n.d.; (3 items) (Folder 5.123)
  - Postcards of the Midwest
    - High School, Joplin, MO; Grand River, Grand Rapids, MI, 1908-1909; (2 items) (Folder 5.124)
  - Postcards of the Northeast
    - New York: Poughkeepsie area, Mohonk, Lake Minnewaska, The College Inn, Slabsides (home of John Burroughs), Gov. Clinton's house, ca. 1904-1908; (4 items) (Folder 5.125)
    - New York: Vassar College Class Day, Class Tree, 1908; (4 items) (Folder 5.126)
    - New York: Vassar College, The Lake, The Circle, The Pines, VC colors, ca. 1904-1908; (7 items) (Folder 5.127)
    - New York: Vassar College, Main, Avery, Library, Chapel, Strong, Main Gate, ca. 1904-1908; (11 items) (Folder 5.128)
    - New York: Minnehaha Falls, n.d.; (1 item) (Folder 5.129)
    - Pennsylvania: Muddy Creek Forks, Horseshoe Curve, 1908, n.d.; (2 items) (Folder 5.130)
  - Postcards of the Southwest
    - Fort Worth, TX, 1909; (1 item) (Folder 5.131)
  - Locations Unknown
    - Breakwater; cliffs. Coastal village, village street, n.d.; (4 items) (Folder 5.132)
    - River scene, Boscastle Harbor, Carnarvon Castle, n.d.; (3 items) (Folder 5.133)
    - Postcards, Miscellaneous (Folder 3.116)
    - Postcards, Miscellaneous (Folder 6.41)
- SERIES IX. MEMORABILIA
  - Honorarium
    - Junior Teacher's License and Assistant Teacher's License, Dept. of Education, City of New York, 1911, 1913; (2 items) (Folder 5.134)
  - Non-Print Material
    - "The Fool's Alphabet," illustrated wall hanging; print of village with mountains in the background, (2 items) (Folder 5.135)
    - "1913" small wall hanging; small tag with illustration of 3 children and a tree; small illustrated calendar, 1913, n.d.; (3 items) (Folder 5.136)
  - Personal Business
    - Bills: photographers, piano company, home maintenance, 1908-1970; (8 items) (Folder 5.137)
    - Itinerary for trip to Japan taken by Mr. and Mrs. Lincoln Brownell and KBC, April 1972; (TS, 3 p.) (Folder 4.62)
    - Address cards kept by KBC, some including biographical information of friends and family, arranged alphabetically, (33 notecards) (Folder 4.63)
    - Return address labels of others saved by KBC, n.d.; (24 items) (Folder 4.64)
    - Namecards of others saved by KBC, n.d.; (7 items) (Folder 4.65)
    - KBC's stationary with letterhead, n.d.; (2 p.) (Folder 4.66)
  - Political Material
    - Women Watcher's Certificates, instructions for women watchers at the polls, 1915-1917; (3 items) (Folder 4.67)
    - Program from 20th Annual Entertainment and Reception, 10th Assembly District Republican Club, January 1918; (1 item) (Folder 4.68)
    - World War I poster, fragile condition, ca. 1914-1918; (1 item, oversized) (Map case drawer 18)
    - Program from Capitol Theatre Grand Gala in honor of Maréchal Foch, November 1921; (1 item) (Folder 4.69)
    - Sample ballot, 10th Assembly District (Brooklyn), November 1931; (1 item) (Folder 4.70)
    - War ration books, WWII, ca. 1941-1945; (2 items) (Folder 4.71)
  - Programs and Pamphlets
    - Miscellaneous programs and pamphlets, 1903-1906; (7 items) (Folder 4.72)
    - Miscellaneous programs and pamphlets, 1907-1915; (3 items) (Folder 4.73)
    - Miscellaneous programs and pamphlets, 1916-1932; (4 items) (Folder 4.74)
    - Miscellaneous programs and pamphlets, (6 items) (Folder 4.75)
    - Programs and Pamphlets, Miscellaneous (Folder 3.118)
    - Programs and Pamphlets, Vassar College (Folder 6.42)
    - Programs and Pamphlets: Miscellaneous (Folder 6.43)
    - Programs and Pamphlets, Miscellaneous (Folder 6.44)
    - Programs and Pamphlets, Miscellaneous (Folder 6.45)
    - Programs and Pamphlets, Miscellaneous (Folder 6.46)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Memorabilia, Miscellaneous (Folder 3.117)
    - Memorabilia, Miscellaneous (Folder 6.47)
    - Memorabilia, Miscellaneous (Folder 6.48)
    - Memorabilia, Miscellaneous (Folder 6.49)
    - Memorabilia, Miscellaneous (Folder 6.50)
  - Scrapbook
    - Scrapbook belonging to KBC, including newspaper clippings, postcards, and programs from trips to England, Norway, Germany, and France. Note: pages are loose, cover and strings were removed, and extra, blank pages discarded, ca. 1952, n.d.; (63 p.) (Box 7)